24petwatch.com 2004-04-02

# 24 PetWatch - Security & Privacy

About your privacy 

At Pethealth, we have been, and continue to be dedicated to protecting your privacy and insuring your information is kept current, confidential and secure. We are committed to using your personal information responsibility and follow strict guidelines of confidentiality and security to safeguard your information.

Pethealth’s ten privacy principles

  1. Accountability  
At Pethealth we mandate to maintain and protect the personal information under our control and have designated an individual within the company to be accountable for compliance with these principles.
  2. Identifying purposes  
We shall identify the purpose of the personal information collected prior to or at the time the information is collected.
  3. Consent  
Individual’s consent will be obtained for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information, except where the law provides an exemption.
  4. Limiting collection  
The personal information we collect shall be limited only to that which is necessary for the purposes identified.
  5. Limiting use, discloser and retention  
Personal information shall only be used or disclosed for the purposes for which it was collected, unless an individual has other wise consented or when it is required or permitted by law. Personal information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of these purposes.
  6. Accuracy  
Pethealth shall keep personal information as accurate, complete and up-to-date as may be necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it is to be used.
  7. Safeguards  
We use electronic and physical safeguards to insure the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information.
  8. Openness  
We will provide information to individuals about our policies and procedures relating to the management of personal information that is under out control.
  9. Individual’s access  
On written request to our Privacy Officer, an individual will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of their personal information that is under our control, and may be given access to that personal information as required and permitted by law. Individuals are entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of that personal information and request that it be amended, if appropriate.
  10. Handling enquires or complaints  
Any questions or enquires concerning compliance with our privacy policies and procedures may be addressed to our Privacy Officer.

Why we collect and use personal information

Collecting personal information about you is essential to our being ale to pride the products and service that best meet the needs of you and your pet. While the personal information we collect may came directly from you, it may also be provided by our affiliates or other third parties (such as employers, insurance brokers or agents, credit organizations, veterinarian professionals, etc)

Personal Information may be used:

  * Verify your identity
  * To determine eligibility for products and services, whether purchased through Pethealth or broker, and for products and services that may be of interest to you from organizations with which we have strategic alliance, and to offer these products and services to you.
  * To process applications for Clients, and provide requested information, products and services
  * To understand and access Clients’ ongoing needs and offer products and services to meet those needs
  * For billing and accounting services relating to our products and services
  * For Client communication, service and administration 
  * For claims administration
  * For internal, external and regulatory audit purposes
  * To comply with legal and regulatory requirements

Consent to use personal information

Consent may be obtained in various ways. We may obtain your express consent or we may determine that consent has been implied by the circumstances. Express consent could be in writing, or verbally in person or over the phone. When we receive personal information from you that enables us to provide you with a requested product or service, your consent to allow us to deal with that person information in a reasonable manner would be implied.

Providing us with your personal information is always your choice. When you request services from us, we ask that you provide information that enables us to respond to your request. In doing so, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure to appropriate third parties of such personal information for these purposes. You also authorize us to use and retain this personal information for as long as it may be required for the purposes described. Your consent remains valid even after the termination of our relationship with you unless you provide us with written noticed that such consent is withdrawn. By withdrawing your consent, or not providing it in the first place, you may limit or even prevent us from being able to provide you with the products or service desired.

In certain circumstance, consent cannot be withdrawn such as were personal information is required for policy issuance or renewal, insurance underwriting or claims administration of current polices. There are also legal exceptions where we will not need to obtain consent or explain the purposes for the collection, use of disclosure of personal information.

Sharing personal information with others

We will not sell client list or personal information to others. In providing our services, we may need to disclose the personal information we collect to affiliates, subsidiaries, successors and other service providers or agents who perform various functions for us (such as underwriters and claims adjusters).

In certain circumstances, we may be required to provide personal information to third parties for legal or regulatory purposes.

We may also use this personal information to assess your future needs and to offer the products and services that may best meet those needs, from affiliates, our reputable organizations or ourselves selected by us. IF you do not wish to receive this offers or such information, please contact our privacy officer.

Keeping information accurate

It is important that your personal information is accurate and complete. Having accurate information about you enables us to give you the best possible service. You have the right to access, verify and amend the information we have about you. We rely on you to keep us informed of any changes, such as a change of address, telephone number or any other circumstances.

How we safeguard personal information

At Pethealth, we employ physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect our systems and all person information under our control against unauthorized access and use. All safety and security measures are appropriate to the sensitivity level of the information collected.

Or service providers and agents are required to maintain clients confidentiality, and may not use the information for any unauthorized purpose.

Employees are governed by strict standards and policies to ensure that personal information is secure and treated with the utmost care and respect.

Please refer to our website at [www.petcareinsurance.com](http://www.petcareinsurance.com/) for a complete copy of our Privacy Policy and [www.pethealthinc.com](http://www.pethealthinc.com/) for a list of our strategic alliances.
